verifyemailaddress.org 2019-03-09

# VerifyEmailAddress.org Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

### 1\. An overview of data protection

#### General information

The following information will provide you with an easy to navigate overview of what will happen with your personal data when you visit our website. The term “personal data” comprises all data that can be used to personally identify you. For detailed information about the subject matter of data protection, please consult our Data Protection Declaration, which we have included beneath this copy.

#### Data recording on our website

**Who is the responsible party for the recording of data on this website (i.e. the “controller”)?**

The data on this website is processed by the operator of the website, whose contact information is available under section “Information Required by Law” on this website.

**How do we record your data?**

We collect your data as a result of your sharing of your data with us. This may, for instance be information you enter into our contact form.

Our IT systems automatically record other data when you visit our website. This data comprises primarily technical information (e.g. web browser, operating system or time the site was accessed). This information is recorded automatically when you access our website.

**What are the purposes we use your data for?**

A portion of the information is generated to guarantee the error free provision of the website. Other data may be used to analyse your user patterns.

**What rights do you have as far as your information is concerned?**

You have the right to receive information about the source, recipients and purposes of your archived personal data at any time without having to pay a fee for such disclosures. You also have the right to demand that your data are rectified, blocked or eradicated. Please do not hesitate to contact us at any time under the address disclosed in section “Information Required by Law” on this website if you have questions about this or any other data protection related issues. You also have the right to log a complaint with the competent supervising agency.

Moreover, under certain circumstances, you have the right to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data. For details, please consult the Data Protection Declaration under section “Right to Restriction of Data Processing.”

#### Analysis tools and tools provided by third parties

There is a possibility that your browsing patterns will be statistically analysed when your visit our website. Such analyses are performed primarily with cookies and with what we refer to as analysis programmes. As a rule, the analyses of your browsing patterns are conducted anonymously; i.e. the browsing patterns cannot be traced back to you. You have the option to object to such analyses or you can prevent their performance by not using certain tools. For detailed information about this, please consult our Data Protection Declaration below.

You do have the option to object to such analyses. We will brief you on the objection options in this Data Protection Declaration.

### 2\. General information and mandatory information

#### Data protection

The operators of this website and its pages take the protection of your personal data very seriously. Hence, we handle your personal data as confidential information and in compliance with the statutory data protection regulations and this Data Protection Declaration.

Whenever you use this website, a variety of personal information will be collected. Personal data comprises data that can be used to personally identify you. This Data Protection Declaration explains which data we collect as well as the purposes we use this data for. It also explains how, and for which purpose the information is collected.

We herewith advise you that the transmission of data via the Internet (i.e. through e-mail communications) may be prone to security gaps. It is not possible to completely protect data against third party access.

#### Information about the responsible party (referred to as the “controller” in the GDPR)

The data processing controller on this website is:

M ~~}0Aq(=n8r~~ iu,6S@acha4Cmw!.g"elf>)-`>"N Pa **& 1'S:**u _U`g_ l1"b=Jp  
P _0Ck|R)7L >M_aul ~~}HX3'"87*;-~~ 2myPInte **%~cJFG pRvu@** r _Mf <SvzAW&~_neVE99IgY}$8t ~~$wV)6{Fqk~~ ( _v|CHO/Jz_ EvRinze ~~& 19T)3~~lun ~~/3~~ t&OaoOi:!!6ernehm ~~kU~~ e _-~3IU_ r _r^N0;48gU_ ) _r|Q_  
Am TKZboS$_+!;*hi4fH7Z#)W0qel _2F$Uvc/f8Hb_ w _vQL/u_ o _Pg_ o{f_N1WP=gci[zK7^n _v_hZ)1Pf &%_3 ~~6gWHC[NjGJ~~ 1 ~~"O &5`F ~=~~  
DE+D][ 6 _O@o_ 7 ~~f3Lr4SF~~ 2 **]#mc2e]aK^sE** 9 ~~ynL#[~~ 2 Kirch ~~EuHv|zyK~~ h2[eimbo ~~Y7G'~~ l _b$?g_ and _$oC_ en ~~~d_hr~~

Telephone: +4 ~~Zum!nD,kQro &~~96352 _^YCT^2X1=7uP_ 75015ep{V:s1Ks5  
Email: p _zQ#_ rivae,9#c ~~`G~~ y@pauli _ZL=-@)_ n _0AK}_ t _6{k{AOK_ e _d0V_ rneEA%t.co9|TqE eD!m ~~j >j~~

The controller is the natural person or legal entity that single-handedly or jointly with others makes decisions as to the purposes of and resources for the processing of personal data (e.g. names, e-mail addresses, etc.).

#### Revocation of your consent to the processing of data

A wide range of data processing transactions are possible only subject to your express consent. You can also revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.

#### Right to object to the collection of data in special cases; right to object to direct advertising (Art. 21 GDPR)

**In the event that data are processed on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. e or f GDPR, you have the right to at any time object to the processing of your personal data based on grounds arising from your unique situation. This also applies to any profiling based on these provisions. To determine the legal basis, on which any processing of data is based, please consult this Data Protection Declaration. If you log an objection, we will no longer process your affected personal data, unless we are in a position to present compelling protection worthy grounds for the processing of your data, that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms or if the purpose of the processing is the claiming, exercising or defence of legal entitlements (objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 1 GDPR).**

**If your personal data is being processed in order to engage in direct advertising, you have the right to at any time object to the processing of your affected personal data for the purposes of such advertising. This also applies to profiling to the extent that it is affiliated with such direct advertising. If you object, your personal data will subsequently no longer be used for direct advertising purposes (objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 2 GDPR).**

#### Right to log a complaint with the competent supervisory agency

In the event of violations of the GDPR, data subjects are entitled to log a complaint with a supervisory agency, in particular in the member state where they usually maintain their domicile, place of work or at the place where the alleged violation occurred. The right to log a complaint is in effect regardless of any other administrative or court proceedings available as legal recourses.

#### Right to data portability

You have the right to demand that we hand over any data we automatically process on the basis of your consent or in order to fulfil a contract be handed over to you or a third party in a commonly used, machine readable format. If you should demand the direct transfer of the data to another controller, this will be done only if it is technically feasible.

#### SSL and/or TLS encryption

For security reasons and to protect the transmission of confidential content, such as purchase orders or inquiries you submit to us as the website operator, this website uses either an SSL or a TLS encryption programme. You can recognise an encrypted connection by checking whether the address line of the browser switches from “http://” to “https://” and also by the appearance of the lock icon in the browser line.

If the SSL or TLS encryption is activated, data you transmit to us cannot be read by third parties.

#### Information about, blockage, rectification and eradication of data

Within the scope of the applicable statutory provisions, you have the right to at any time demand information about your archived personal data, their source and recipients as well as the purpose of the processing of your data. You may also have a right to have your data rectified, blocked or eradicated. If you have questions about this subject matter or any other questions about personal data, please do not hesitate to contact us at any time at the address provided in section “Information Required by Law.”

#### Right to demand processing restrictions

You have the right to demand the imposition of restrictions as far as the processing of your personal data is concerned. To do so, you may contact us at any time at the address provided in section “Information Required by Law.” The right to demand restriction of processing applies in the following cases:

  * In the event that you should dispute the correctness of your data archived by us, we will usually need some time to verify this claim. During the time that this investigation is ongoing, you have the right to demand that we restrict the processing of your personal data.
  * If the processing of your personal data was/is conducted in an unlawful manner, you have the option to demand the restriction of the processing of your data in lieu of demanding the eradication of this data.
  * If we do not need your personal data any longer and you need it to exercise, defend or claim legal entitlements, you have the right to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data instead of its eradication.
  * If you have raised an objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 1 GDPR, your rights and our rights will have to be weighed against each other. As long as it has not been determined whose interests prevail, you have the right to demand a restriction of the processing of your personal data.

If you have restricted the processing of your personal data, these data – with the exception of their archiving – may be processed only subject to your consent or to claim, exercise or defend legal entitlements or to protect the rights of other natural persons or legal entities or for important public interest reasons cited by the European Union or a member state of the EU.

### 3\. Recording of data on our website

#### Cookies

In some instances, our website and its pages use so-called cookies. Cookies do not cause any damage to your computer and do not contain viruses. The purpose of cookies is to make our website more user friendly, effective and more secure. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer and stored by your browser.

Most of the cookies we use are so-called “session cookies.” They are automatically deleted after your leave our site. Other cookies will remain archived on your device until you delete them. These cookies enable us to recognise your browser the next time you visit our website.

You can adjust the settings of your browser to make sure that you are notified every time cookies are placed and to enable you to accept cookies only in specific cases or to exclude the acceptance of cookies for specific situations or in general and to activate the automatic deletion of cookies when you close your browser. If you deactivate cookies, the functions of this website may be limited.

Cookies that are required for the performance of the electronic communications transaction or to provide certain functions you want to use (e.g. the shopping cart function), are stored on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in storing cookies to ensure the technically error free and optimised provision of the operator’s services. If other cookies (e.g. cookies for the analysis of your browsing patterns) should be stored, they are addressed separately in this Data Protection Declaration.

You can revoke your consent for cookies from our website at any time by visiting the [Cookie Control Center](https://www.verifyemailaddress.org/cookie-control.html).

#### Server log files

The provider of this website and its pages automatically collects and stores information in so-called server log files, which your browser communicates to us automatically. The information comprises:

  * The type and version of browser used
  * The used operating system
  * Referrer URL
  * The hostname of the accessing computer
  * The time of the server inquiry
  * The IP address

This data is not merged with other data sources.

This data is recorded on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator of the website has a legitimate interest in the technically error free depiction and the optimization of the operator’s website. In order to achieve this, server log files must be recorded.

#### Request by e-mail, telephone or fax

If you contact us by e-mail, telephone or fax, your request, including all resulting personal data (name, request) will be stored and processed by us for the purpose of processing your request. We do not pass these data on without your consent.

The processing of these data is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR, if your request is related to the execution of a contract or if it is necessary to carry out pre-contractual measures. In all other cases, the processing is based on your consent (Article 6 (1) a GDPR) and/or on our legitimate interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR), since we have a legitimate interest in the effective processing of requests addressed to us.

The data sent by you to us via contact requests remain with us until you request us to delete, revoke your consent to the storage or the purpose for the data storage lapses (e.g. after completion of your request). Mandatory statutory provisions - in particular statutory retention periods - remain unaffected.

### 4\. Social media

#### Social media plug-ins with Shariff

We do use plug-ins of social media networks on our website and its pages (e.g. Facebook, Twitter, Google+, Instagram, Pinterest, XING, LinkedIn, Tumblr).

As a rule, you will be able to recognise these plug-ins because of the respective social media logos that appear. To warrant the protection of data on our website, we use these plug-ins only in combination with the so-called “Shariff” solution. This application prevents the plug-ins that have been integrated into our website from transferring data to the respective provider as soon as you enter our website.

A direct connection to the provider's server shall not be established until you have activated the respective plug-in by clicking on the affiliated button (which indicates your consent). As soon as you activate the plug-in, the respective provider receives the information that you have visited our website with your IP address. If you are simultaneously logged into your respective social media account (e.g. Facebook), the respective provider will be able to allocate your visit to our website to your user account.

The activation of the plug-in constitutes a declaration of consent as defined in Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR. You have the option to revoke this consent at any time, which shall affect all future transactions.

### 5\. Analysis tools and advertising

#### Google Analytics

This website uses functions of the web analysis service Google Analytics. The provider of this service is Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

Google Analytics uses so-called cookies. Cookies are text files, which are stored on your computer and that enable an analysis of the use of the website by users. The information generated by cookies on your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the United States, where it is stored.

The storage of Google Analytics cookies and the utilization of this analysis tool are based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator of this website has a legitimate interest in the analysis of user patterns to optimize both, the services offered online and the operator’s advertising activities.

**IP anonymization**

On this website, we have activated the IP anonymization function. As a result, your IP address will be abbreviated by Google within the member states of the European Union or in other states that have ratified the Convention on the European Economic Area prior to its transmission to the United States. The full IP address will be transmitted to one of Google’s servers in the United States and abbreviated there only in exceptional cases. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google shall use this information to analyse your use of this website to generate reports on website activities and to render other services to the operator of this website that are related to the use of the website and the Internet. The IP address transmitted in conjunction with Google Analytics from your browser shall not be merged with other data in Google’s possession.

**Browser plug-in**

You do have the option to prevent the archiving of cookies by making pertinent changes to the settings of your browser software. However, we have to point out that in this case you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website to their fullest extent. Moreover, you have the option prevent the recording of the data generated by the cookie and affiliated with your use of the website (including your IP address) by Google as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

**Objection to the recording of data**

You have the option to prevent the recording of your data by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. This will result in the placement of an opt out cookie, which prevents the recording of your data during future visits to this website: Google Analytics deactivation.

For more information about the handling of user data by Google Analytics, please consult Google’s Data Privacy Declaration at: [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=de).

 **Contract data processing**

We have executed a contract data processing agreement with Google and are implementing the stringent provisions of the German data protection agencies to the fullest when using Google Analytics.

**Archiving period**

Data on the user or incident level stored by Google linked to cookies, user IDs or advertising IDs (e.g. DoubleClick cookies, Android advertising ID) will be anonymized or deleted after 14 month. For details please click the following link: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7667196?hl=de>

#### Google AdSense

##### Visitors within the EEA (non-personalized ads)

This website uses Google AdSense, an ad embedding service provided by Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

We use Google AdSense in the “non-personalized” mode. Contrary to the personalized mode, the ads are not based on your previous user patterns and the service does not generate a user profile for you. Instead, the service uses so-called “context information” to choose the ads that are posted for you to view. The selected ads are thus based e.g. on your location, the content of the website you are visiting at the time or the search terms you are using. To learn more about the distinct differences between personalized targeting and targeting that has not been personalized by Google AdSense, please click on the following link: <https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/9007336>.

Please keep in mind that even the use of the non-personalized mode of Google Adsense results in the potential archiving of cookies. According to Google, these cookies are used to combat fraud and misuse. These cookies will remain on your device until you delete them.

The use of Google Adsense in the non-personalized mode is based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDRP. We have a justified interest in the analysis of user patterns to be able to optimize both, our web presentation and our promotional activities.

Google is certified in accordance with the “EU-US Privacy Shield.” The Privacy Shield accord was executed between the European Union and the United States with the aim of ensuring that European Data Protection Standards are observed in conjunction with the processing of data in the United States. Every company that is certified in accordance with the Privacy Shield regulations undertakes to comply with these data protection standards.  

You have the option to autonomously adjust the advertising settings in your user account. To do so, please click on the link provided below and log in: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

For more information about Google’s advertising technologies, please click here:  
<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>  
<https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/>.

##### Visitors outside the EEA

This website uses Google AdSense, a service for the integration of ads. The provider of this service is Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

Google AdSense uses so-called "cookies"; i.e. text files that are stored on your computer and that make it possible to analyse your use of this website. Google AdSense also uses so-called Web Beacons (invisible graphics). These Web Beacons can be used to analyse information, such as visitor traffic data, on this website.

The information generated by the cookies and the Web Beacons concerning the use of this website (including your IP address) and the delivery of advertising formats are transferred to a Google server in the United States, where they are archived. Google may share this information with Google contracting partners. Google shall, however, not merge your IP address with any other of your data stored by Google.

The storage of the AdSense cookies is based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in the analysis of user patterns, in order to optimize the operator’s web offerings and advertising.

You can prevent the installation of these cookies by making a pertinent adjustment to your browser software settings; however, we have to point out that in this case you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website to their fullest extent. By using this website, you declare your consent to the processing of the data we collect about you by Google in the manner described above and agree to the aforementioned purpose of use.

### 6\. Plug-ins and Tools

#### YouTube

Our website uses plug-ins of the YouTube platform, which is operated by Google. The website operator is Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

If you visit a page on our website into which a YouTube plug-in has been integrated, a connection with YouTube’s servers will be established. As a result, the YouTube server will be notified, which of our pages you have visited.

Furthermore, YouTube will be able to place various cookies on your device. With the assistance of these cookies, YouTube will be able to obtain information about our website visitor. Among other things, this information will be used to generate video statistics with the aim of improving the user friendliness of the site and to prevent attempts to commit fraud. These cookies will stay on your device until you delete them.

If you are logged into your YouTube account while you visit our site, you enable YouTube to directly allocate your browsing patterns to your personal profile. You have the option to prevent this by logging out of your YouTube account.

The use of YouTube is based on our interest in presenting our online content in an appealing manner. Pursuant to Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR, this is a legitimate interest.

For more information on how YouTube handles user data, please consult the YouTube Data Privacy Policy under: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>.

#### Google reCAPTCHA

We use “Google reCAPTCHA” (hereinafter referred to as “reCAPTCHA”) on our websites. The provider is Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

The purpose of reCAPTCHA is to determine whether data entered on our websites (e.g. information entered into a contact form) is being provided by a human user or by an automated program. To determine this, reCAPTCHA analyses the behaviour of the website visitors based on a variety of parameters. This analysis is triggered automatically as soon as the website visitor enters the site. For this analysis, reCAPTCHA evaluates a variety of data (e.g. IP address, time the website visitor spent on the site or cursor movements initiated by the user). The data tracked during such analyses are forwarded to Google.

reCAPTCHA analyses run entirely in the background. Website visitors are not alerted that an analysis is underway.

The data is processed on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. It is in the website operators legitimate interest, to protect the operator’s web content against misuse by automated industrial espionage systems and against SPAM.

For more information about Google reCAPTCHA and to review the Data Privacy Declaration of Google, please follow these links: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en> and <https://www.google.com/recaptcha/intro/android.html>.

Last updated: Jan 30, 2019
